Inventory of the John W. Rodeffer Papers 1891-1900
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
John W. Rodeffer Papers 1891-1900
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2008.124
0.50
The John W. Rodeffer Papers are a collection of letters to John W. Rodeffer. Correspondents include family members including his mother and sister, various female friends, male friends, and others. The letters include accounts of daily life and similar information from the 1890s-1900.
Rodeffer, John W., 1864-; Rodeffer Family arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 11/25/2008.
Biographical Note
Per 1900 census, John W. Rodeffer was born in Ohio in December, 1864. His parents were Conrad and Hannah Rodeffer. Per 1870, 1880 and 1900 census, the family lived in Rockingham, Virginia. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/John W. Rodeffer.
Scope and Contents
The John W. Rodeffer Papers are a collection of letters to John W. Rodeffer. Correspondents include family members including his mother and sister, various female friends, male friends, and others. The letters include accounts of daily life and similar information from the 1890s-1900.
Additional Information
Related Materials
An embroidered ribbon was removed from Box 1, Folder 2 and transferred to Series 1: Textiles, Sub-series 3: Personal Clothing of the Manuscripts Artifact Collection (Mss. 1.03).
Separated Materials
An embroidered ribbon was removed from Box 1, Folder 2 and transferred to Series 1: Textiles, Sub-series 3: Personal Clothing of the Manuscripts Artifact Collection (Mss. 1.03).
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence
Geographic Name:
Rockingham County (Va.)--History--19th century.
Topical Term:
Women--Virginia--Social life and customs.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Family, 1894-1898; id43959
  - Letters from Malinda Rodeffer (mother) and Laura Rodeffer (sister), 1896-1897; id43962 (Folder 1)
  - Letters from Cousins and Uncle, 1894-1898; id43963 (Folder 2)
- Women, 1891-1900; id43960
  - Stella Cline, 1891-1898; id43964 (Folder 1)
  - Anna, 1891-1895; id43965 (Folder 2)
  - L.R.S. (Laura R. Shaver), 1893-1896; id43966 (Folder 3)
  - Katie, 1895-1897; id43967 (Folder 4)
  - Hattie D. Long, 1892-1893; id43968 (Folder 5)
  - Etta Cline, 1899-1900; id43969 (Folder 6)
  - Various Female Friends, 1892-1897; id43970 (Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous, id43961
  - Letters from Male Friends, 1893-1899; id43971 (Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, id43972 (Folder 2)
  - id44827 (Folder 15)